so I just got a couple of passages from
a suitor and imagine minute I am 74 you
can occur
it's the one wire and the wanderer
Deegan akka says I hold the view that
everything is unacceptable to me
but later on in the suit
the the buddha starts talking about the
body can feeling he says but Hagee base
honor this body which is material made
of the four Great elements produced by
mother and father an accumulation of
rice and porridge of the nature of
impermanence rubbing crushing
disintegration and destructions should
be seen as impermanent as an arrow as
misery as an affliction as other as
disintegrating as empty as not so what
all those things have in common all
those what are they having Kannan
do you know yeah well so the beginning
sense said that its material is made of
the four Great elements its make a
mother and father
it's accumulated that's a cape and
accumulation of rice and porridge this
is the nature of impermanence rubbing
crushing disintegration destruction
there are being crushing this
integration destruction not self yeah
what all those things are there it's
another what a listenings have in common
well there there it's like that it's
basically it's not mine it's not
produced by me it's it's made by my mom
and that's that what's the main
characteristic of something that would
define something as yours and something
is not yours so what's the difference
between the two so something that's mine
is in some way there's some pleasure of
alternate more more it is because of the
pleasure sure but how does that manifest
something that's yours which of course
it's yours because it's present yeah
times they manifested how is the
pleasure manifested you know how exact
which is yours how is that which is mind
manifested as opposed to that which is
not yours
now you might experience pleasure and
boat on a boat okay what's the
difference out it comes first you know
both come first in a way they're
supposed to come from the same place
basically the one that is yours in the
one that isn't evils are differentiated
by the control or lack of it and that's
exactly the common thread you have no
control yeah and any of those
descriptions it just reinforces that
same thing yeah you are not the master
of that body which is you yep it's
matter so it's like it's kind of like a
smell - exactly it's four Great elements
exactly made by mother and father so the
way it came to be
accumulation of random rice porridge
yeah nothing to do with subject to rubbing
nothing to do with subject to rubbing
disintegration friction basically
falling apart and is it there it's other
so yes
your body is closer to the like when you
perceive others you clearly apply their
bodies and all yoga so the nature I have
no control over others to that extent
well your body's closer to that yes do
you think others are then it is what you
think your body is for you yeah that's
my thoughts my translation so para is
common translation for that is foreign
or aliens mmm-hmm but yeah just it's
although it's like yes
even though future say this photo that
other bodies according to you it's not
your body well you want to go your body
as foreign as other bodies do so that's
the thing so at the beginning he says
the body is material it is made of the
four Great elements made by your mother
and father but it says it should be seen
as yeah it should be seen as in
permanent suffering as a disease as an
abscess as an arrow
so if the body were not truly yeah in
permanent disease an arrow and so on you
can't see it like that
yeah but it is truly like that but the
reason you don't see that because you're
ignoring it literally you're ignoring
those characteristics because they are
unpleasant and as the Buddha said yeah that
and as the Buddha said yeah that
ignorance is gratuitous it shouldn't be
there but it's beginningless there was
no point before which you are not
ignorant then you suddenly became
ignorant so that's what you should make
the effort to see it correctly the way
it actually is and stop ignoring it and
you will undo the ignorance or
a video so can you say that if you
should say the body should be seen in
this in this way in these ways it's like
these should be the significance yeah
what if you yeah the context of your
daily experience
yeah be that yeah making the f27s at the
back of your mind and I see what you
think yeah let it in deal then while you
go about and do things with your body
and then you will realize how less and
less you'll be able to engage with
things that require passion they require
taking body to be yours they require you
to ignore the nature
the body being subjected to destruction
and non control yeah
because I think people will begin by
having this notion of what my body and
then I have to think of my body like
that yeah and so and that's that's one saying
yeah and so and that's that's one saying
the difference is between establishing
the context and and and attending to it
like that it's basically you you can't
do it even if you want you're not
supposed to make your body no oh it's
it's actually ugly could you be doing in
the basis of your ignorance first that's
exactly yeah so I'm ignoring the true
nature of the body and now on top of
that I'm just trying to paste the new
nature that I've been told it's a better
one and that's how people usually
misunderstand the whole set of katana
for that matter yeah you think you
should be attending to every second of
your body and not let it slip because it
slips it slips back into permanence no
destruction and control no you want to
surmount so yeah there is the exist I
have a control over this body to some
extent it's not denying it but you want
to see that doesn't matter how much
control you can exercise upon your body
fundamentally it's fully within the fact
that the body is given there first and
you have no control over that and if the
body is were to be taken away it will be
taken away you can't stop that suits
instead of trying to like override your
sense of control denied like it's a
permanent disability permanence in
permanent you actually want to first
acknowledge it and then see beyond it
see the context that it's created to it
and and that's why it's effortless my
original idea if you establish the
context that this body is subject to
impermanence to destruction to
everything else and you let it let I am
subject to that because that's what the
nature of the body is okay now I just
need to protect that context don't get
carried away don't forget about it don't
get distracted in regard to it separate
in order to do that you need to sort of
almost like rewrite the significance of
body for you because you'll have these
notions of body as sure high body you
know that I need to worry well you need
to you need to see a problem the way
things are for you in order to start
making effort
maybe fix it yeah sort it out yeah but
what you need to do first truly is
restrained the out pose of the body the
actions that the fully rooted in in in
you taking body like yours and you
control it then you're very right to it
you feel entitled to it yeah then you
like there is nothing wrong we can
pleasure through the body because you
know the body is yours the pleasure is
available why not more listening so you
need to start restraining that in order
to get to see it correctly and you
wouldn't do that unless you see unless
you have understood to some extent there
is a problem with the way things are
problem main problem being you're
subjected to suffering on account of
that very body yeah it's because if you
aren't changing your behavior you are
simply contradicting the direction of oh
yeah well it's like like as we said
before you know your goal is to do and
the sutra says the same actually it's
the similar from the sutras your goal is
to light the fire by collecting some
like good wood that you can basically
rub and create a spark and get home far
gone but you keep the wood in the water
yeah and you're not making effort to
take it out and dry it out and then
you're made trying to make the fire at
the same time with a but wood it's
totally completely futile and that's
exactly people who are practicing Dhamma
and the teaching without keeping the
pieces yeah or even without being
celibate
there's just contradiction in terms yeah
so so the Buddhist goes on so say won't
you see the body's impermanent as
suffering as a disease and obsesses and
Harrow because misery is an affliction
as other as disintegrating as empty as
not self for one seeing this body has
impermanent to suffer in my face
whatever desire for the body's affection
for the body giving into the body that
is a bummer so if you maintain the
context of the correct nature of the
body all the things they've been
dependent upon absence of that
conviction will disappear things such as
desire here will wrong views yeah but
see that thing you need to see the body
correctly but it is because now when
your mind is affecting with ignorance
when the only way you relate two bodies
to sensuality what you think the body is
it's basically the product of you taking
wrongly your own body it's not what the
body is yeah so you need to start start
restraining that and then start on doing
it in order to arrive at the point where
you recognize this is what my body is
saying then dwell and develop that
content recollection recollection simply
recollected mass of the body mindfulness
of the body it's basically just
understanding what the body is exactly
you don't need to fabricate anything you
know you just need to undo stuff yes sir
that's obscuring it they stop which
you're responsible
covering up yeah active the right
understanding of for police yeah didn't
a the obvious nature they will become
obvious and apparent here and now if if
you stop looking away from it if you
stop ignoring it
there's another suitor in the sanger
tunic I become the sangeeta this says
that a uninstructed bhiku a virtuous
picking should contemplate the five
aggregates matter even possession
determinations consciousness as these
things hmm and then it says it if it
does then he you may become a certain
funder and I so to punish should
contemplate these things if you do see
it's the same thing today so so body
matter through the five aggregates all
essentially have this same significance
well yes and not just that they have the
same significance same calm same nature
they're all within the same thing so
it's not that you start first with
Martinus to the body and then you go and
find your feeling your perceptions your
intentions left and right from it yeah
it's good innit
yeah so if you have mindfulness with the
body right mindfulness it the five
aggregates right cuz you can't
experience or this is my aggregate of
form and it's separate from these other
areas and you can kind of look between
them and so you are the whole fine
it's always the five not three and a
half so whether you're mindful of the
five aggregates or might float the body
is the dark as the as the disease is
misery you're mindful of the same thing
and this passion will be the result of
it so that's or even like Annie says
look you can become sort of own by doing
it exactly because even as an as a is a
new newcomer so to speak a beginner to
the to the practice if you are actually
instead of trying to find a magical
meditation technique they will sort your
issues out if you actually start
practicing virtue and we're investing
effort in sense restraint and then dwell
on the nature of what you already are
subject to death subject to illness
subject to disease to old age and all
other accident misfortune you don't need
to wait and quite
opposite you don't need to wait for
those things to happen we have to do it
before doesn't happen but they are
obviously there which is the entire
point of lay life for most people it's
actually engaging with things that will
help them distract themselves from the
obvious that you will lose everything
that you will die go sick lose your
health lose your strong illusion you
lose all these things yet all the air
food you make is just to help you ignore
that that's what people are afraid to be
alone afraid to be without distractions
that's why boredom always turns into
existence your dread if it's prolonged
so give me company give me family given
distraction give me things to do give me
some purpose because otherwise I'll be
trying in myself yeah and time
and often people then take on to
practice the Dharma for those very wrong
reasons not because they won't want to
do what they are they just want down
were there to take them on a whole new
level of basically four great forgetting
what they are but if you take the right
order of practice sense you a virtual
sense restraint and then actually
acknowledging the nature of your own
existence which is what mundane Drive
you pretty much is then getting the
right view of a solar panel well you
won't have to wish it so it will have to
happen because you're not running away
from your own existence any more mundane
right view is there is another various
father there there is giving there is so
you know there are things that are
unfathomable there things that action
there are actions basically there is
there is responsibility yeah yeah means
there is also like the fact that I don't
know that is the lack of my knowledge
that is the fact you'd meet all those
things you have knowledge so mundane
right view is basically the right
acknowledgment or acknowledgement of the
right things there are things that are
not in my control in my life depends
upon yeah and again you can ask anyone
even a non Buddhist person who is not
interested in meditation already
formal practice fundamentally they would
come down and admit yeah of course I
know that I cannot escape that yeah I
know that I cannot escape sickness but
you take it will taken a lot of effort
just admit that temporarily everything
else then it's done is to cover it up
and forget about it and that's exactly
why you remain enslaved by those things
because of your own effort to remain
yeah very prison those things can't imprison
very prison those things can't imprison
you you in prison yourself through those
things by by respecting your doing his
response to them yes absolutely actually
possessions ownership everything
everything evidence so that's really
what the right practice is nothing else
nor the technique necessary if you keep
your sealer restrain your senses and
then admit what's obvious yeah
don't distract yourself from obvious
context of your life yeah that's your
technique but that that can be very very
unpleasant mm-hmm but it's only
unpleasant because you never dealt with
it you never wanted to deal with
anything so now it's okay emulator lots
of it probably you didn't want to deal
with it for lifetimes hmm but the sooner
you start the better
yeah
this suture then goes on to talk about
feelings hmm I just says something it's
quite interesting it says aggravation
that there are these three feelings
Pleasant feeling painful feeling neither
painful nor pleasant feeling huggy face
my cousin I given it anyway I give a
sauna it was his clans name that's what
they say I don't know I'm not sure
anyway I give a sauna almost ever occasion one
I give a sauna almost ever occasion one
feels a pleasant feeling on that
occasion one feels neither painful
feeling nor and neither painful nor
pleasant feeling and that's occasion one
feels only a pleasant feeling on
whatever occasion won't feel the painful
feeling one feels neither a pleasant
feeling nor and neither painful nor
pleasant feeling on that occasion one
feels only a painful feeling and on
whatever occasion so in other words
whatever occasion what's felt that's the
only thing that's felt yeah that's the
only thing that's felt there is only
that feeling it and I think if you think
about that things generally people would
wouldn't understand things like that no
they would say well no hang on a minute
to take a lot of undoing to arrive just
a bit yeah
because you people you'll have a
particular feeling right now laced with
desire yes a and it for something
thinking that if I do that then I'll
have this other feeling yeah as if those
two feelings are both present like that
one in the future
well they are present us to the assumed
sense of self yeah that's independent of
what I was being felt which is a
contradiction in terms but it's a
contradiction they will remain real as
such for as long as you don't face it
and undo it
yeah so that's the thing a common person
thinks they're separate from the
feelings feelings happen to me yeah like
this feeling I like that feeling
I remain unchanged for all these
feelings coming and going yeah but if
you look at it you realize in the same
as we describe the body you are
subjected to the feeling not other way
around yeah
and that's where the Buddha would ask
people who would say yes feeling is mine
as in I'm first feelings belong to me as
a result of it
the belugas world which feeling then
belongs because if you were in control of your
because if you were in control of your
own feelings you will never feel
unpleasant because literally whenever
this pleasure touches you all you do all
your efforts are rooted in trying to
overcome it to everything everything is
rooted in trying to overcome pain yet
here you are claiming you are in charge
of your pain but all those intentions to
remove the pain are all within that pain
absolutely all intentions to protect the
pleasure are within that pleasure all it
takes intentions to run away from the
neither pain nor pleasant nor no
pleasure as in boredom basically are
within that the wailing so how can you
as any attempts to escape the feeling
impossible because there's no outside of
the feeling there
you're always within the feeling and the
fact that they will change means you're
not always within the same feeling yes
because if it were just one feeling well
you could then at least say well this
feeling doesn't change yes so it's okay
but they do change so the container
within which you're fully enclosed that
you cannot step outside of it changes on
its own and that change is actually
external to you you cannot do count even
and think about her yeah not even
conceive it theoretically how it becomes
the other you just subjected to this and
then it in you and everything and then
we just find out you subjected something
else that that induce another that was
colored by that everything's color by
that and everything is within that
that's what it's meant like the actual
change as in impermanence as in subject
to change subject impermanence is abrupt
it's not actually observable if it's
observable means you're separated from
it and you can observe it point a at
point B no you are within point a there
is no point B within point ay no it's
just point a then you realize oh now
it's another point in oh if you can
remember the previous one but only on
the con the ground of the current yeah
presently doing feelings so yes you can
have same pleasure experience in the
future but it's not the same pleasure in
that sense because it's another yes yeah
there is only one feeling there is only
one feeling I mean you can find other
feelings but they're all gonna be within
yes yes yeah this one fundamentally
there is only one feeling felt yeah
pain pleasure or neither and again
realizing that you realize that the
whole subject to change the whole the
whole existence it's actually not rooted
in you and not rooted in your point of
view but the rooted in things arising on
their own man as in I'm subjected to
this feeling that has a reason on its
own and so basically burdens me as such
so recognizing that that it's not rooted
in you basically it's it's recognizing
what truly impermanence is as in subject
to change which is what unknowable so he
says once you set this Ernie what feels
only one kind of feeling he then says
aggravation a pleasant feeling is
impermanent determined dependently
arisen with the nature of as the nature
of wasting a way of passing a way of
fading away of cessation same for
painful feeling and in the important
thing for somebody who wants to
contemplate this is to realize there is
no in-between you only find yourself you
can only find yourself fully within
already feeling that order Hindus yeah
it's not their displeasure pleasure and
now is disappearing and now there is
pain again that assumes you as an
external point of view to this process
but it isn't it can't be because you you
are within it and that's um that would
also be putting you first of course
you're the one that's unchanged protest
changes feel exchange I remain unchanged
yeah yeah I'm gonna being different
about it but you still have a grain of
assumption that you are separate from it
to the extent that you can observe to
and in between and how one becomes the
other no you find yourself within
feeling it already induce and then also
how does the feeling change that's not
on you yeah I think I mean how does a
feeling change question implies how can
I step outside of this feeling and see
how it becomes another as it how can I
read repossess it how can I regain the
control of its own origin and cessation and
of its own origin and cessation and
that's how I'll be safe that's why that
view it's not just like a level of
theories deeply emotionally rooted view
both I need safety in regard to this
that I'm subjected to yeah the safety
Safari possess the way it came to be
have been charged so that's why you
automatically start assuming the
external from it as means of dealing
with it but you realize no I have no say
in it and nor can I step outside of it
that's why it like you have to stop
acting out of your feelings as incense
restraint comes first
yeah allowed them to endure and then you
get to understand their nature yeah you
do it doesn't matter what matter doesn't
matter what feeling is present whether
it's pleasant unpleasant or neutral your
restraint has been developed beforehand
and now you realize and because its
present on its own that's why it will
have to change and that's the
understanding of son man whatever yeah
has a reason oh that's why those are
known as the legends that's what has the
nature to cease not because I can
observe it cessation but because it came
on its own and I'm not saying it this
nature that's yes exactly
no it's all its nature to see it's not
like that yeah look look it disappeared
that's why it's a permanent no that's
almost like yeah yo you're not sorry
you're missing it
so recognizing there is no in between
the two feelings there is only one
within which you are subjected to and
you have to endure it and then you just
like next time you like as we done
though the reflection about what's your
current mood is it present a present
neutral oh it's Pleasant so now you did this
oh it's Pleasant so now you did this
your thinking time passes the same
feeling induce sometimes for a day of to
even the same mood will endure in their
general level but then next day knows
like you don't feel right nothing there
is discomfort fundamentally everything
is fine actually
there's nothing particularly bothering
you but there is some weird I don't know
discomfort of some weird anxiety or
something in the back of your mind
without anything specific and that's it
now you just recognize that change has
occurred yes as it now you're subjected
to something else so if you stop
assuming outside of it stop trying to
get rid of it
stop trying to distract yourself wrong
you'll be come from
with a very abrupt nature of change
within which you are you cannot conceive
external and that's how you will develop
this passion towards it because there
will be no self-centered point-of-view
to maintain that passion anymore because
any point of view you have is within the
present enduring feeling or any point of
view you have is within the present
enduring body that is the dart misery
pain subjective change
it's the same principle what are you
taking on level of the feeling rolling
level of the body you want to see that
you are within it not other way around
there as in you are in close by so
whether you look beyond it your look and
your thoughts are beyond that is within
the necessary basis of present enduring
body it's within the necessary basis of
present enduring feeling and then the
fact that present enduring feeling is
felt differently at different times
means you have no saying its internal
working so to speak it's inconceivable
because you can only be subjected to
serious all you need to do is then
restrain your effort your attitude
towards the feeling that's felt
pleasantly restrain understand your
attitude towards feeling it's felt
unpleasantly and again keep your
attitude in check don't distract
yourself towards the feeling that felt
neutrally because how these feelings are
felt or why it's actually relevant and
only what is relevant is the Europe
pressed by them which is why I
automatically want to act and get rid of
them or prolong them and so on
yeah he goes on to say seeing in this
way a noble disciple turns away from
Pleasant feeling turns away from painful
feeling turns away from neither painful
nor pleasant feeling turning away he
becomes dispassionate and his passion
he's liberated liberated not depressed
anymore by any change they might occur
within the five years and then he goes
up places he finishes it says in this
way Peggy Basinger I pick him with the
liberated mind doesn't agree with anyone
doesn't disagree with anyone whatever is
said in the world is expressed by him
without holding phase fully independent
a green would disagree with anyone means
basically adopting or relating to their
view externally to that extent but now
you've abandoned everything literally
whatever you said it's factual because
none of it is rooted in trying to gather
into the feelings or repossess the body
and so on there's no agreement no
disagreement it's just factual so two
other hands they don't agree with each
other yeah two independent individuals
yeah externally yet they're in perfect
externally yet they're in perfect
agreement yeah no it's making effort to
agree with that's what they can argue I
can't argue something it's either
they're wrong or they'll agree with you
if you're in Ireland because you're not
agreeing with you Peter Green with
universal nature of things which is what
you fooling this to develop which is why
you did abandon your sense of self and
the whole thing which is what makes you
not but yes if you hear that like if an
owner on hears that he can solve
extremely conceited as it did when they
blew the first yeah basically spoke to
that man said no it looked very bright
whose teachings you follow I follow no
much teaching
I am I only that I am the supreme leader
of gods and humans nobody's my match yet
it's like a few early factual statement
is understood the universal truth of it
all feed himself as a result of it but
this man is I go WOW okay so good for
your friends and dismissed whatever
whatever yeah they're do you he's got to
follow himself yeah that's how it sounds